# **Maddy Woodrum**

New York, NY ⋈ madzno12@gmail.com 🖈 maddywoodrum.dev 🔘 madzno

I'm a Software Engineer with experience using various technologies, in particular JavaScript/Node.js and Ruby. Previously, I was a Registered Nurse and Nurse Practitioner, where I learned that I enjoyed thinking critically and solving problems. Most recently, I built Twine , a drop-in auto-scaling WebSocket infrastructure for modern web applications that provides connection state recovery.

# **SKILLS**

Launguages

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, Ruby, SQL, Go

Cloud

AWS, DigitalOcean droplet, Heroku

**Runtimes, Libraries & Frameworks** 

Node.js, Express, React, Sinatra, Socket.io

Misc. Technologies

Linux, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Redis, OOP, Git/GitHub, REST APIs, HTTP, WebSocket, Postman

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Creator, Software Engineer,** *Twine* 

Aug 2023 – present

Twine is a drop-in auto-scaling WebSocket infrastructure for modern web applications that provides connection state recovery. Twine drops into an existing application via client and server libraries and is automatically deployed into a user's AWS account.

- Architected and constructed a drop-in auto-scaling WebSocket infrastructure using various AWS services (EC2, DynamoDB, Elasticache for Redis, Elastic Beanstalk)
- Built a Node.js backend REST API to facilitate communication with the Twine Server and persist received data in DynamoDB and Redis
- Built a decoupled Redis pub/sub mechanism for sending data received from backend servers out to clients via a WebSocket connection
- Implemented automatic connection state recovery mechanisms that provide in-order delivery of missed data and mitigate client disruption in the case of a dropped WebSocket connection
- Wrote cron job logic to automate the removal of stale data from Redis
- Containerized server code in a Docker container for deployment
- Authored comprehensive technical case study, readable at: https://twine-realtime.github.io/
- Collaborated remotely with an international team of four engineers across three time zones using agile workflow

#### **Software Engineer,** *Self-Employed*

2021 - 2023

Developed freelance and open-source applications including:

- Request-Inspect: Tool for collecting, inspecting, and debugging Webhooks (JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, MongoDB, PostgreSQL)
- **Shopper-Cart:** Database-backed e-commerce app (JavaScript, Node.js, React, MongoDB)
- **Contacts-App:** CRUD contacts manager (Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS)

#### Nurse Practitioner, Registered Nurse,

Sep 2015 – Aug 2023

Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center

• Worked as a part of a multidisciplinary team, charge nurse, and preceptor to new graduate RNs fostering a collaborative environment and honing excellent communication skills

### **EDUCATION**

**Launch School,** Software Engineering, Capstone Program \(\mathbb{Z}\)

2021 - 2023

A multi-year mastery-based curriculum teaching full-stack engineering fundamentals from first principles.

**Hunter College,** Master's Degree, Nursing Science, Summa Cum Laude

2018 - 2020

Villanova University, Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Cum Laude

2011 - 2015